One year ago, Apple Inc attempted a hostile rebranding of a letter's AI by changing it from
artificial intelligence to Apple intelligence. At the time, people called it genius, but ultimately
the move failed when we learned that AI is just actual Indians. This year, Apple is back at it,
attempting another hostile rebrand by taking the gimmicky web development trend of glass morphism
and renaming it liquid glass, which is the new design language in iOS 26 that maximizes transparency.
I have to admit, it does look nice, but Microsoft also tried glass morphism on Windows Vista
over a decade ago, which is considered by many to be one of the worst Windows distros ever released.
It kind of feels like Apple just needed to do something to refresh the design system and ran out
of ideas, but liquid ass wasn't the only big announcement. What's far more exciting are things
like JavaScript, Linux containers, and Apple's new paper that discovered how AI is not all that
intelligent. In today's video, we'll break down everything you need to know about Apple's worldwide
developer conference. It is June 11, 2025, and you're watching the code report. One of the most
interesting announcements for developers is that Mac OS now has its own Linux containerization
framework optimized for Apple Silicon. Typically, if you want to run a Linux container,
you can install Docker desktop or podman, but now you can bypass all these tools and run containers
natively on your Mac. Each container runs on its own time UVM and should achieve better performance
than shared VMs like Docker. That's pretty cool because several years ago, I switched from Mac to
Windows for development because of WSL, and this feels like a move in the right direction to get
me back into the Apple Colt. In addition, the Swift programming language also got some updates
like the Java Swift project, which allows you to publish a turd by incorporating beautiful
Swift code into a Java project, and Swift can also safely mix with CNC++. The elephant in the room
is Apple Intelligence. Last year, they made it sound like they were going all in on AI, but after
it flopped hard, they decided to hardly mention it this year. Apple does have some new foundation
models that seem pretty good, but nothing special. As long as you trust, the Trustme Bro benchmarks.
These models will run on device mostly, but complex AI can be generated securely in their private
cloud, which is an oxymoron by the way. And at some point, they're expected to support Gemini
models in addition to open AI. What's funny though is that Apple also just released a paper titled
the Illusion of Thinking that talks about how large reasoning models are actually not that special.
They're basically just pattern matching machines that don't actually think in the way humans
think about thinking. I've always said that LRMs are way overhyped, but the timing of this paper
is sus because Apple is way behind in the AI race at this point. The thing most people are talking
about though is liquid glass. Some people love it, but most seem underwhelmed. It's just an
incremental change, but if we keep going in this direction, eventually the entire UI will be invisible,
and maybe that was the plan all along as man prepares to merge with machine. Only time will tell,
but if you need some UI inspiration, the best place to get it is on mobin.com, the sponsor of
today's video. I've been using mobin for over five years now, and what they do is provide highly
detailed breakdowns of every screen and popular applications. As a developer, you can steal or I
mean get inspired by these patterns and implement them in your own applications. You can analyze entire
user journeys, UI elements and screens from over a thousand highly successful apps, and you can even
bring them directly into Figma to kickstart your design process, give mobin.com a try for free
right now with the link below. This has been the code report, thanks for watching, and I will see you
in the next one.